LEAH BANKS

□ leahb_96@hotmail.co.uk
□ 07939 263 330
□ London

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/leahrbanks https://github.com/leahbanks https://leah-banks.netlify.app

PROFILE

I am a recent graduate of the industry-leading Northcoders bootcamp, where I gained proficiency in JavaScript, React, HTML, CSS and Node. I am a logical thinker with a background in Customer Happiness, Team Management and the arts, pursuing my first role in Front End Development - a field that combines my professional knowledge of user experience, with my passion for creative problem solving and my desire for accessibility and inclusivity within the world of tech and beyond.

SKILLS

Programming Languages: Javascript, TypeScript

Front End: React, React Native, HTML,

Cascading Style Sheets (CSS), Document Object

Model (DOM). Awareness of: SASS

Back End: Express.js, PostgreSQL, Test Driven Development (TDD), REST APIs, Node.js, OAuth

Testing: Jest, SuperTest

Applications/Version Control: Git,

Project Management/Design: Trello, Atlassian, Jira, Confluence, ReTool, Excalidraw, Canva

PROJECTS

Portfolio

<u>https://leah-banks.netlify.app</u>

A responsive mobile-first application and a collection of my recent projects.

NC News

https://nc-news-lb.netlify.app

NC News API

https://nc-news-81lq.onrender.com/api

Through the Fog

https://github.com/leahbanks/FE-through-the-fog

EDUCATION

University of Westminster

BA Fine Art Mixed Media First Class Honours

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

 Between September and November 2022, I undertook a career transition and self-taught basic Javascript in order to kickstart my career in Software Development.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Trainee Full Stack Developer

Northcoders

November 2022 - March 2023

- · Pair programming to write production-ready code front-end and back-end frameworks.
- · Gained awareness of WCAG, PWAs and a mobile-first approach, using Lighthouse to improve accessibility.
- · Gained hands on experience with React, React Router, HTML5 and CSS3 to create front-end web applications from wireframes.
- Built a full-stack mobile application in a team, using agile methodologies to ensure efficiency and transparency.
- Used Express.js to build server endpoints and develop RESTful APIs using CRUD operations.
- Utilised Git for version control best practice.

Customer Happiness Team Leader

Oddbox

April 2022 - September 2022

- Managed and supported a team of 6 agents to meet weekly KPI targets, holding fortnightly and quarterly reviews.
- Proactively handled any tech issues that arose, alerting and working with the relevant teams to implement solutions and minimise impact on the customer.
- Worked closely with the Tech team to manage the website's Al Chat Bot and optimise its performance.
- · Worked closely with the Product team to relay feedback on the website, test new functionality and inform decisions on the user journey during the migration to a new subscription management system.

Customer Happiness Executive

November 2022 - April 2022

Oddbox

- Addressed complaints and gueries with efficiency and empathy.
- Regularly surpassed weekly KPI targets (200 tickets solved)
- Managed and updated online FAQs to improve user experience and streamline customer contact.
- Safely managed customer data to conform to GDPR guidance
- · Worked collaboratively within my own team and other teams using systems such as ReTool and Atlassian (Confluence and Jira).

Visitor Experience Assistant

Serpentine Galleries

April 2019 - November 2020

- · Acted as a first point of contact for all visitors and internal staff.
- Used creative eye and close attention to detail to design effective Visual Merchandising and drive sales.

Gallery Host

June 2018 - April 2019

Serpentine Galleries

· Developed public speaking skills by delivering exhibition tours and presentations to the public.

Further work experience is available upon request.